<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
 <title type="text">My Blog: Posts tagged 'Lab1'</title>
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.example.com/feeds/Lab1.atom.xml" />
 <link href="http://www.example.com/tags/Lab1.html" />
 <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-tags-Lab1-html</id>
 <updated>2025-01-06T04:35:04Z</updated>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Lab 1 Mason Tozer</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.example.com/2025/01/lab-1-mason-tozer.html?utm_source=Lab1&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-2025-01-lab-1-mason-tozer-html</id>
  <published>2025-01-06T04:35:04Z</published>
  <updated>2025-01-06T04:35:04Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>The Unknown Author</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;h1 id="cs-2613-lab-1-git-and-frog-basics"&gt;CS 2613 Lab 1: Git and Frog Basics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the introductory lab in this course, we covered some of the basics that will be used throughout the course. Some readings were given to be done before the first lab, such as reviewing the syllabus, Git and Frog basics, as well as a basic Shell background. We started by having a quick discussion of a brief course overview, along with some Q&amp;amp;A regarding the syllabus and other CS courses that were similar to this. We then installed frog and the tools required to use it, along with the python library pygments, which is used by frog for its syntax highlighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-          &lt;a href="https://docs.racket-lang.org/frog/index.html?q=frog"&gt;Frog&lt;/a&gt; is simply a static website generator and was written using the programming language Racket. Frog is going to be used in this course as a blog for our journal entries. Content on our ‘blogs’ will be written in either markdown or scribble formats.  Though we also learned that markdown is much more commonly used in the industry, thus markdown is generally the more encouraged format for this class. We practiced building our journal entries into &amp;lsquo;blogs&amp;rsquo; on a static website, to ensure they were able to build correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discussed Git, and how it will be used throughout the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-          &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/"&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source version control system, that is used mainly by programmers to record changes in their projects. Git is well suited for projects of any size, and is notable for its speed and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were asked to read the git-quickref page on D2L, and then we started with some Git basics. We learnt that Git has a heavy integration within the system’s terminal, and has many commands used for recording the changes within your project. Some of the notable ones we have learnt and will use within this course are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-          A user can create a new repository (the storage location where you can track and manage the changes in your files and directories) using the &lt;em&gt;git init -b NAME&lt;/em&gt; command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-          They can add a remote repository (a storage location for your repository that is not within your system files. In our case, we are creating a remote within the FCS git repository) using the &lt;em&gt;git remote add NAME LOCATION&lt;/em&gt; command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-           A user can add files to the local repository using the command _git add FILENAME&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;           A user can create a snapshot of their project in its current state, and have it saved to their local repository using the &lt;em&gt;git commit&lt;/em&gt; command&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-           They can then upload the changes made in their local repository to their remote location repository using the &lt;em&gt;git push –all REMOTE REPOSITORY NAME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some concepts of this lab were familiar from other CS courses that I have previously taken at UNB, such as the use of git, which I have previously used in my software engineering class. Though some concepts were new to me, such as Racket, Frog, and the markdown format. I caught on to the basics of these concepts pretty quickly, but I am eager to master them throughout our course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.example.com/2025/01/lab-1-mason-tozer.html?utm_source=Lab1&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry></feed>