<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
 <title type="text">My Blog: Posts tagged 'Lab4'</title>
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.example.com/feeds/Lab4.atom.xml" />
 <link href="http://www.example.com/tags/Lab4.html" />
 <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-tags-Lab4-html</id>
 <updated>2025-01-15T04:35:04Z</updated>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Lab 4 Mason Tozer</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.example.com/2025/01/lab-4-mason-tozer.html?utm_source=Lab4&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-2025-01-lab-4-mason-tozer-html</id>
  <published>2025-01-15T04:35:04Z</published>
  <updated>2025-01-15T04:35:04Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>The Unknown Author</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;h1 id="cs-2613-lab-4-continued-work-in-racket"&gt;CS 2613 Lab 4: Continued Work in Racket&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our fourth lab in CS 2613, we started with the reading of &lt;a href="https://www.cs.unb.ca/~bremner/teaching/cs2613/books/FICS/Structures.html"&gt;unit 4 from A Functional Introduction to Computer Science&lt;/a&gt;. We were given new questions to think about for out next lab:  - The programming languages we will study this term are all dynamically typed. This means that not only the value but also the type of variables can change at runtime. Why does this make testing even more important? - What kind of software problems is testing not well suited to find? - Why might mutable state (e.g. instance variables in Java) make writing unit tests harder? As well, we went over the questions presented in our previous lab, lab 3: - The programming languages we will study this term are all _dynamically typed. This means that not only the value but also the type of variables can change at runtime. Why does this make testing even more important? - What kind of software problems is testing not well suited to find? - Why might mutable state (e.g. instance variables in Java) make writing unit tests harder? After the group discussion, we dove right back into our learning in Racket. We created out Lab folder for the day, and started with &lt;a href="https://www.cs.unb.ca/~bremner/teaching/cs2613/books/FICS/Structures.html#%28part._.Correctness%29"&gt;exercise 11&lt;/a&gt; from our text. Today&amp;rsquo;s coding lesson focused on recursive algorithms with Racket, and our program had us simulating natural numbers in an abstract way. We then started working on a second function from exercise 11 to simulate natural numbers. We then learnt about structural recursion, and used it on the natural numbers functions that we created earlier in the lab. We were then giving the reading of section 5.1 and 5.2, to be read before the next lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of simulating natural numbers in this manner, and recursion within Racket, were new concepts to me within this lab. Though, I have worked with the concept of recursion in previous classes, such as CS 2383, data structures and algorithms, as well as originally learning it in our second Java class, CS 1083. I got to continue practice in Racket, which still feels like a very new skill to me, as well as getting to try implementing recursion with Racket. I found today&amp;rsquo;s lab to be overall a bit confusing to be fully honest. I recognize that I need to catch up on my knowledge within Racket, and I plan to do so over the next few days and the weekend so that I am feeling more prepared for Monday&amp;rsquo;s class. Though I don&amp;rsquo;t fully understand Racket now, I am eager to learn it and to try my best to excel in this class. I am grateful to have the text A Functional Introduction To Computer Science as a handy reference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.example.com/2025/01/lab-4-mason-tozer.html?utm_source=Lab4&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry></feed>